今年，香港藝術發展局修訂條例草案。
本會現在恢復二零一三年税務修訂條例草案二讀辯論，審議條例草案嘅委員會主席梁繼昌議員會就委員會嘅報告向本會發言，梁繼昌議員。
主席。
在 my capacity of chairman of the Bills Committee on Inland Revenue Amendment Bill Two Hundred and One Three。
我 wish to report on the work of the Bills Committee.
我將聚焦於主要議題，由法案委員會考慮。
The main objects of the bills are first to put in place a legal framework for Hong Kong, to enter into tax information exchange agreements with other jurisdictions.
and secondly, to enhance the existing exchange of information arrangements under comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreements.
In respect of tax types and limitation on information disclosure.
The purpose for introducing the changes is to meet the latest international standard for exchange of tax information.
bills committee generally supports the proposals in the bill in view of the importance of Hong Kong to maintain its reputation as an international business and financial centre, committed to upholding tax transparency and combating tax evasion.
and to be able to pursue comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreements successfully with trading partners.
在course of deliberations.
成員們有然而表達了關心，關於放寬限制信息披露的範圍。
The possible additional burden on taxpayers in respect of retention.
和Reporting of tax information.
The adequacy of the safeguards for protecting taxpayers' privacy and confidentiality of tax information exchanged.
The oversight and scrutiny of the administration's compliance with the disclosure procedures.
as far as the use of tax information for non-tax related purposes.
One major proposal of the bill, Mr. President.
是 to allow the commissioner of inland revenue to disclose tax information generated prior to the effective date of the relevant comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreement, or, if applicable, the tax information exchange agreement.
如果他滿意，那信息關乎執行有關協議的條款，或税法的管理或執行，於申請國的領土。
在 respect of any period that starts after the date on which the relevant agreement comes into operation.
although the administration has advised that the existing record keeping requirements under the inland revenue ordinance
which stipulate a seven-year period for the retention of business and rent records， will remain unchanged.
Some members of the Bills Committee are concerned that the proposal will allow a requesting tax authority to ask for information generated more than seven years before the relevant agreement comes into operation.
它被建議，先生，行政應設定一個時間限制。
on the period for which provision of retrospective information will be considered.
或 expressly confine such disclosure only to information that is necessary and direct for a specified purpose.
The administration.
In response to this demand, has explained that.
under both comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreements.
和税信息交換協議。
requests for exchange of information have to meet a standard of foreseeable relevance.
which is a safeguard against fishing expeditions.
In addition, under the Inland Revenue Disclosure of Information Rules.
The Commissioner of Internal Revenue will not entertain a request for information exchange.
unless he is satisfied.
Upon the examination of the particulars provided by the requesting partner.
that the standard of foreseeable relevance.
Among other criteria, is met.
The administration has advised that, as far as the standard of the Organisation for Economic Cooperation and Development (OECD) is concerned.
The formulation.
foreseeable relevant has been adopted to mean necessary and relevant.
Furthermore, even when the inland revenue department acts on a valid exchange of information request.
and exercises its information gathering power to approach a person for the relevant information.
The person has no obligation to provide to the department.
for exchange of information purposes.
信息，which is not in his possession or control.
and is not required to be capped.
或Beyond the statutory retention period.
under the inland revenue ordinance.
因此，行政考慮到沒有需要設置時間限制於提供回溯性資訊的期間，於兩項協議下。
成員們對法案委員會也關心有關在法案下要設立的保障。
和未來税信息交換協議。
to ensure that taxpayers' privacy and confidentiality of information exchanged.
都 duly protected。
The inland revenue department will not release information for inappropriate reasons.
The administration has advised that.
After the legal framework for tax information exchange agreements is in place.
In order to afford legal protection to taxpayers in terms of privacy and confidentiality of information exchanged.
它將跟隨現行的策略，即全面避免雙重課税協議。
to strive to provide relevant safeguards in the text of their relevant tax information exchange agreement.
這些 safeguards將包括， among others。
to exchange information only upon request.
Only to disclose information which is foreseeably relevant.
to treat information received as confidential.
not to disclose information requests to a third jurisdiction, etc.
The administration has assured the Bills Committee that each comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreement, or tax information exchange agreement signed.
將會被實施作為國內的補助性立法，受立法會否決的影響。
The existing inland revenue disclosure of information rules.
Providing for domestic statutory safeguards in addition to those provided in individual agreements.
Will be extended and become applicable to exchange of information under both agreements.
Some members also raised concerns, in particular.
on the disclosure of information subject to legal professional privilege.
The administration has advised that there is no obligation on a contracting party of either of the two agreements to supply information covered by legal professional privilege.
The restriction on disclosure of legally privileged materials.
是 legally binding on the inland revenue department.
Furthermore.
It is stated in the commentary on the exchange of information article of the OECD Model Tax Convention that a requested jurisdiction may decline to disclose information.
relating to confidential communications between attorneys.
solicitors.
或其他委任律師代表的職務，作為其，和客户，至於程度，該通訊受到國內法保護，不公開。
在處理税payer的appeals和資訊披露。
法案委員會Notes，那《內地税收披露資訊規則》。
has put in place a notification and reveal system.
在處理交換資訊要求及相關Appeals。
例如，作為一個納税人提出異議的程序。
to the disclosure of or or part of the information that the commissioner of inland revenue is prepared to disclose to the requesting partner.
There was a suggestion that the administration should should put in place.
An independent oversight body.
to ensure that the inland revenue department will deal with individual requests.
以一個fair and consistent manner。
and that the actions taken and decisions made by the department.
會嚴格 adhere to internal procedures and guidelines.
on this issue.
The administration has explained to the Bills Committee that whether or not Hong Kong can pass OECD's evaluation on its compliance with the latest international standard for exchange of information in September this year.
將 largely hinge on the availability of a legal framework for tax information exchange agreements.
It is therefore critical to proceed with the proposals of the bill.
to put in place such a legal framework in a timely manner.
since the suggestion to set up an independent oversight body to monitor the inland revenue department's compliance with the disclosure procedures.
會 lead to some structural changes to the existing system.
The administration considers it premature to take it forward.
In parallel with the proposals in the bill.
Without gauging the views of the concerned parties and the public.
它將然而尋求改善對程序遵守的監察，在長遠。
the bills committee notes that to abide by a new requirement of OECD.
The administration is prepared to allow future contracting parties of comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreements to use the information exchanged for non-tax related purposes.
This does not involve, Mr. President, any amendments to the Inland Revenue Ordinance in the current legislative exercise.
The non-tax-related purposes for tax information exchange.
Are to be governed by the terms of the relevant agreements.
The administration has explained that under the latest version of the OECD exchange of information article.
非税相關目的，必須是目的，為税信息交換。
may be so used under the laws of both parties to the relevant agreement.
和使用的資訊交換，for such purposes.
must have the prior authorisation of the competent authority of the supplying party.
Moreover, OECD only allows the sharing of tax information by the tax authorities of the receiving party with other law enforcement agencies.
和司法權力在那個管轄區。
On certain high priority matters.
for example, to combat money laundering, corruption, and terrorism financing.
The privacy commissioner for personal data has expressed concern that the use of tax information exchange.
Under the comprehensive avoidance of double taxation agreements for non-tax related purposes, may not be entirely consistent with the existing exemption provisions in respect of prevention and detection of crime under the personal data privacy ordinance.
The administration has explained that, on every future occasion of intended use of tax information, for specified non-tax related purposes.
The Inland Revenue Department will not consent.
我強調，將不會同意，通過請求一個承諾方。
如果相關政府部門在香港 raise objection。
或如果such use of information is not covered by the current exemption as provided under Section 58 of the Personal Data Privacy Ordinance,
In relation to crime under the laws of a place outside Hong Kong, with which Hong Kong has in place legal or law enforcement cooperation.
The administration has advised that, under the laws of Hong Kong.
Tax information may only be used for limited non-tax related purposes.
such as recovery of proceeds from drug trafficking.
organised and serious crimes and terrorist acts.
The administration has assured members that.
在簽訂新全面避免雙重税收協定的未來。
它將不會輕易地否認最新版本的資訊交換條款。
unless both jurisdictions have similar legislation on use of tax information for non-tax related purposes.
Together with law enforcement cooperation arrangement in place between them.
Mr. President.
法案委員會支持第二讀的法案。
Neither the administration nor the Bills Committee will move any committee stage amendments.
The following part of the speech carries my personal comments on the bill.
作為 personal observation。
The bill enables Hong Kong to comply with the bare minimum of the latest exchange of information standard.
It does not put Hong Kong at the forefront of international tax cooperation initiatives.
作為一萬二百二十成員的全球透明度與資訊交換與税務目的的國際組織。
香港是唯一沒有法律框架進入兩 tiers。
香港是經過兩階段的雙向審查，由全球論壇。
which evaluates jurisdictions compliance with the international exchange of information standard.
Phase one of the peer review, Mr. President, was completed in October 2011.
在December 2012，The Global Forum launched a phase two peer review on Hong Kong.
which evaluates Hong Kong's implementation of the exchange of information standard in practice.
and examines whether Hong Kong has taken forward the recommendations proposed by the Global Forum during the phase one peer review process.
如果香港fails the phase two peer review,
香港 may run the risk of being labelled as an uncooperative jurisdiction.
which will be damaging to our position.
作為國際金融中心。
In addition.
其他 jurisiction may also impose unilateral sanctions on Hong Kong.
It is therefore critical for Hong Kong to have in place the legal framework for the tiers now, before the Global Forum finishes the phase two peer review in September 2013.
先生，我已審視了安全措施，已提出要實施於法案，或任何未來協議，以維護機密性質，並防止將受法律專業保護的資訊，傳遞給第三方國家。
The safeguards, in my views, are at par with international standard and practice.
on 18th of June, 2013.
The leaders of G8, Mackinac Island and North Island.
One of the achievements of the meeting.
Was a commitment by the leading economies to shake up international corporate tax rules.
The ten-point lock-on declaration calls for tax authorities to share information automatically.
它也敦促國家改變那讓多國企業將利潤跨國度轉移以避税的規則。
and require them to report what tax they pay where.
香港 may not be subscribing to these principles yet.
但係，會唔會係香港的長遠利益，要被標榜為一個不合作的司法管轄區？
或一 jurisiction， which attracts business， due to its secrecy rules and opaque business and tax regime.
such types of offshore havens， will soon have no place on earth.
In conclusion, Mr. President.
since the policy direction of the bill is clear and equitable.
and it is fairly and reasonably draft.
I would urge my honourable colleagues in this chamber from across the parties to support this bill. Thank you, Mr. President.
呢位議員。
主席，二零零八年金融海嘯之後，好多西方國家咧都面臨嚴重嘅財政赤字，佢哋千方百計增加財政收入，而不斷提高税務交換資料嘅廣度同深度咧，肯定係方向之一。大家都記得零九年四月咧喺倫敦峯會上邊咧，二十國集團同意打擊避税天堂。
o e c d隨即公佈三種名單，即係黑名單、灰名單同埋白名單。當時咧，法國曾經要求將香港同埋澳門列入作灰名單，即係代表呢個地區咧屬於打擊避税不足地區。消息傳出咧，引起好大嘅震動，因為香港作為國際金融中心、啊貿易同埋航運。
中心一旦被列為灰名單咧，會產生。
嚴重嘅後遺症。
後來咧，透過中央政府嘅協助，極力阻止。
本港被列入灰名單，結果咧。
係有一啲其他嘅地方咧，被染灰，而本港咧就避免跌入灰名單。香港咧亦都爭取到寶貴嘅時間咧，修改相關嘅法例，回應國際社會嘅關注。喺二零一零年，政府修訂咗税務條例，令到經合組織税收協定版本二零零四年版本中。
有關資料交換嘅條文咧，得以喺香港落實。實際上咧，就係讓税務局咧可以因應全面性協定夥伴提出嘅要求，收集同埋披露某啲納税人嘅資料，即使有關資料咧並不關乎本地税務事。呢個做法咧，同國際標準接軌，而香港政府嘅努力咧，亦都得到。
國際社會嘅認同。二零一一年十月喺經合組織有關税務透明化同埋有效資料交換嘅全球論壇上咧，通過咗香港嘅評估報告，對香港提致力提高税務透明度嘅工作咧係予以肯定。而喺法例修訂之後咧，香港亦都採用。
咗國際性嘅資料交換準則，對擴大本港全面性被免雙重課税協定網絡咧，有好大幫助。至今咧，香港已經簽咗，據我瞭解係二十九份全面性嘅協定。而喺二零一零年咧法例修訂之前咧，其實香港只係簽訂咗五份嘅協定。
到咗最近咧，G八元首喺不愛爾蘭召開峯會嘅時候咧，與會者其中一項共識咧，就係要聯手打擊。
係跨境逃税或者跨境避税，同時促請各國修改法例，令到而家屬於合法嘅避税行為咧都有機會變成非法。雖然喺峯會裏邊提出好多措施都未列出具體細節，不過咧外界預計咧九月起聖彼得堡舉行嘅G二十峯會咧，或者會簽署正式協。
所以咧。
估計打擊避税天堂嘅工作咧會陸續推展。今次政府提出税務條例嘅修訂咧，係避免誒將香港列入為避税天堂名單嘅第二波工作，因因為咧最新嘅資料交換國際標準裏邊咧係要求一個税務管核區同其他税務管核區咧應該。
同同時具備全面性協定同埋交換協定兩種資料。
嘅交換工具，針對呢個標準咧，喺全球論壇將喺今年九月咧再進行第二階段嘅評估，所以咧喺而家完成協定嘅法定法律框架咧係十分重要。可以預計咧，國際社會對於税務資料交換咧，只會不斷提高要求，亦都不斷收緊。
平核嘅準則，相信香港咧日後咧都會面對一輪又一輪嘅平核。而民建聯嘅立場係誒支持最低度嘅修訂，以符合資料交換嘅制度，令到香港能夠喺通過不同階段嘅評估，避免受到避税天堂嘅指控。主席喺過去多次相關討論嘅誒。
而相關討論裏邊咧，議員基本嘅立場都係相同嘅，就係喺税務資料交換呢個問題上咧，我哋。
誒係唔需要超英趕美喺國際社會嘅要求底下咧，香港呢一個細小而開放嘅經濟體，誒只需要咧係不只係只需要喺最後嘅階段咧，符合最低嘅要求，避免跌入避税天堂嘅名單當中，噉。
背後嘅理據當然大家都理解啦，因為香港税率低、税種少，資料制度嘅誒框架底下咧，相信咧係香港企業咧係誒會係不斷被要求咧係提供資料，而香港可能向
外要求提供資料嘅機會咧，係相對少嘅。
主席，所以民建聯咧係認同今次政府提出嘅修訂建議，亦都認為咧係符合最低嘅規定嘅要求。咁包括當局咧係考慮到對有關追索性嘅評估同埋海外税務調查嘅誒。
税務資料嘅要求等等，咁另外政府都承諾咧，只會根據國際協定嘅條文同埋香港嘅法例咧，披露所要求嘅有關資料。面對國際社會對提高税務
透明度、防止同埋打擊避税嘅期望越嚟越高咧。香港社會，尤其是商界同埋中小企咧，其實都要提高警覺，亦都要有心理準備，因為喺好多國家眼裏邊咧，我哋香港都成日被定性為或者被認為係避税天堂。呢個背後嘅想法咧有兩大理由。第一咧就係香港。
單獨執行。
誒地域管制。
地域管轄權只對香港境內個人收益同埋企業利潤徵實徵税。
內地對外，對於外商投資，有一隻咧實行，有一有一係列嘅免税政策。
以致咧，如果有香港公司嘅利潤主要係喺境外產生，好容易咧就形成咗雙重免税。第二咧就係香港税項較少啦，税税率較低，企業所得税咧亦都較其他國家低，加上香港唔使收利息税啦、資本增值税或者遺產税等，咁亦都容易咧引起大量外。
國嘅資金流入，所以咧為咗避免香港社會成為國際啊社會嘅眼中釘，或者被認為不。
誒被視作不合作嘅税務管轄區咧，我哋係有需要修改法例配合國際税務標準嘅基本要求。
既然香港要履行國際社會嘅責任，配合國際税務嘅標準，民建聯咧係促請税務局要為我哋納税人咧把好關。對於其他地區提出嘅資料交換要求咧，係取態必須從嚴；只要披露咧，係要求最低限度嘅資料，同時咧確保交換嘅資料咧。
只向有關當局披露，而保障咧納税人嘅利益，而回應咧企業嘅擔心。最後咧，民建聯係誒支持今日嘅修訂法例。咁考慮到政府同其他地方簽訂嘅全面性避税雙重。
徵税協定咧，更能夠促進香港商業活動嘅措施。我哋促請當局咧喺日後嘅工作重點咧，係放喺誒擴擴展香港同。
同我哋主要貿易同埋投資夥夥伴嘅全面性協定網絡。本人緊接陳志恆主席。善總嘉言。
先生，我會像回歸到我的請求，為一個獨立監察委員會為IRD。
Administration's current proposal does not properly address my concerns.
The Global Forum on Transparency and Exchange of Information for Tax Purposes, the Global Forum, has recommended reinforce the legal framework to facilitate effective exchange of information.
One of the vital enhancement to the framework would be establishing an independent oversight committee.
行政總署的建議擴展內税部使用者委員會的範圍是不滿意的。
The users' committees would have limited access or exposure to information, since the IRD would provide all the reports, the breakdowns by the types of information requested, etc. to the committee. A flaw in this system is that the IRD would control all information distributed to the users' committees.
另一個 discrepancy 是，that the users committees would not deal with the confidential information and would not have no role in conducting reviews on individual cases.
I fully support protecting taxpayers' privacy and confidentiality of information disclosed in EOI, but it is essential for someone to monitor the information that R&D shares.
According to the administration, setting up an independent review panel under the law to monitor the handling of exchange information requests is premature.
I disagree. In order to avoid complex scenarios in the future, it is vital that we take early precautions.
In order to continuously maintain Hong Kong's reputations as international financial centre, we must strengthen the framework by constantly filtering and monitoring the systems in place.
Creating an independent oversight committee would ensure the IRD would deal with the individuals' OI's requests in a fair and consistent manner.
And all that actions taken and decisions made strictly adhere to the internal procedures and guidelines.
utilising an independent oversight committee has several advantages. It is generally much more cost-effective compared with the forming of.
performing and implementing something later.
also，since experts are involved。
An informed bias is kept to a minimum.
The independent oversight committee can also operate a meeting as a.
as an as an internal check between the IRD and the public.
It is the role the committee can help the public understand technically complex issues by publishing reports that committee that communicate the facts in ways the public can understand.
現有的。
The existence.
of an independent oversight committees can have impact on the quality of fairness and fact finding.
even before the committee gains access to relevant information.
When research is done in the knowledge that outside utilities,
outside and that an outside entity will be reviewing the research methods and findings. There's an increased sense of accountability.
Government or corporate research entities must ensure the standard of the work is acceptable, especially because in the long run it will be more costly and time-consuming if they are forced to go back and correct mistakes. When the independent oversight committee detects and
errors or deceptions.
作為過去成員的Operations Review Committees of the ICAC，我理解如何一個獨立的監察委員會應該運作。
The ICC OLC reviews every complaint made and cases investigated by ICC.
irrespective of the size and severity of the crime.
成員們，
No investigation can be terminated with ORC consent.
This successful relationship between Rousey and ICA has enhanced the.
productivity of ISAC.
Why wouldn't RLD would form such a committee similar to VRC?
President, I sincerely hope that the administration sees the necessity of forming such committees. Furthermore, the Security and Futures Commissions also have a similar set up. The SFC has a process review panel. I hereby urge the government to look into the matter. Thank you.
有冇其他委員要發言？
如果冇咧，我現在請財經事務及副務局局長發言答辯咧。局長答辯之後，辯論即告結束。局長，誒主席，首先我要感謝二零一三年税務修訂誒。
條例草案，下稱條例草案。
法案委員會主席梁繼昌議員、副主席陳建波議員，各位委員同埋立法會秘書處同事所付出嘅努力，令審議工作咧得以順利完成。
我亦要感謝咧各位議員支持條例草案喺今日恢復二讀辯論，並多謝咧李慧瓊議員同埋謝重佳議員剛才發表嘅寶貴意見。
政府當局喺今年四月將條例草案提交立法會審議。
法案委員會共召開咗六次會議，並邀請咗業界同埋相關持份者就條例草案表達意見。
條例草案嘅目的係修訂税務條例，讓香港可以。
簽訂獨立嘅税務資料交換協定，我下稱交換協定，並優化現行全面性，避免雙重徵税協定，我下稱全面性協定嘅資料交換安排，以符合國際標準。
特區政府一直致力與主要貿易及投資夥伴建立全面性協定網絡，為跨境商貿活動提供明確嘅税務安排同埋雙重課税寬免，以促進本港同埋世界各地之間嘅貿易、投資同埋人才互通。
截至二零一三年六月底，香港已跟二十九個税務管核區簽訂全面性協定，當中十一個係香港首二十位嘅貿易夥伴。
香港作為國際社會中負責任嘅一員，一向致力提高税務透明度，同埋防止逃税活動。
所有香港簽訂嘅全面性協定中，均已加入資料交換條文。
國際間對提升税務透明度以防止同埋打擊逃税活動嘅期望越趨殷切。
根據經濟合作同埋經濟合作與發展組織税務透明化及有效交換資料全球論壇，我查清全球論壇所述。
國際最新嘅資料交換標準係一個税務管轄區必須同時備有全面性協定同埋交換協定呢兩種資料交換工具。
香港現行法例並不容許香港簽訂交換協定。
香港作為全球論壇嘅成員，現正接受成員互。
現正接受成員相互評估，藉以檢視香港是否符合國際嘅資料交換標準。
香港第一階段嘅評估已於二零一一年十月完成。
按全球論壇所述，香港可否通過第二階段評估，主要決定於是否具備簽訂交換協定嘅法律框架。
假如香港未能通過第二階段評估，
很可能會被國際社會視為不合作嘅税務管轄區。
呢個不但有損香港嘅國際聲譽，亦會削弱香港作為國際。
商業同埋金融中心地位同埋競爭力。
而其他税務管轄區亦有可能對香港作出單方面嘅制裁。
鑑於全球論壇將於本年九月審議香港嘅第二階段評估報告，我哋有必要盡快修例，使香港具備簽訂交換協定嘅法律框架，以爭取順利通過第二階段嘅評估。
與此同時。
為使我哋日後嘅全面性協定商議工作能夠有所突破，我哋需要透過法例修訂，以便在有必有，以便在有需要時協定下嘅資料交換安排，可涵蓋不同嘅税項種類，以及讓税務局局長喺信納有關請求。
嘅資料。
關乎協定實施後嘅税務評估時。
可披露該等資料。
在法案委員會會議上，我哋與委員就如何保障納税人私隱及資料嘅保密性。
以及建議修訂對納税人嘅影響進行咗詳細嘅討論。
我希望喺度總結有關資料交換安排嘅保障。
首先喺條例草案獲得通過後。
政府喺兩種協定下嘅資料交換安排，均會繼續採取現時高度慎密嘅雙重保障措施。
以維護納税人嘅私隱同埋所交換資料嘅保密性。
在一方面，我哋會一貫地爭取將有關保障措施納入日後所簽訂嘅協定文本中。
有關保障措施包括只披露可預見相關嘅資料。
所獲取嘅資料必須保密。
不得向第三司法管轄區披露資料等，而有關協定會以本地附屬法例嘅形式，經立法會以先訂立後審議嘅程序實施。
另一方面，税務豁廕披資料披露規則會適用於日後簽訂嘅協定，作為本地嘅法定保障。
有關規則定明，協定夥伴必須在資料請求中再述嘅詳情。
以顯示其請求符合可預見相關嘅標準。
至於條例草案中關乎披露限制嘅建議，
正如我哋喺法案委員會會議上清楚表明，我哋無意偏離現行就交換嘅資料施加限制嘅政策。
即向協定夥伴披露嘅資料，必須關乎於。
協定條文。
實施以後嘅任何期間。
我哋建議。
微調現行嘅披露限制，目的係容許在有關協定實施前產生嘅資料，也可以進行交換。
但大前提係税務局在審視個協定夥伴在資料交換請求所提供嘅詳情後，認為有關請求符合可預見相關嘅。
嘅標準，而所要求嘅資料係關乎於有關協定實施以後嘅任何期間所施行有關協定嘅條文，或執行協定夥伴嘅税務法律。
藉住放寬喺資料交換所涵蓋嘅税項種類。
我哋可我哋渴望有更大彈性去遊説主要税務管轄區與香港開展全面性協定嘅商討工作。
喺條例草案獲得通過之後，我哋會實際，我哋實際上會採取正面列載嘅方式。
於每份協定列明所涵蓋嘅税項種類。
有關協定將透過立法會嘅先訂立後審議嘅方式實施，成為本地附屬法例。
部分議員同埋代表團體曾就條例草案會否影響納税人嘅責任或法律專業保密權表達關注。我重申，條例草案並無改變現行税務條例下嘅紀錄備存規定。
因此，即使税務局根據一項有效嘅資料交換請求，行使其蒐集資料權力，要求某人提供相關資料，該人亦沒有責任為著資料交換目的而向税務局提供按税務條例。
無需予以備存或超過法定備存時限嘅資料。
至於法律專業保密權喺全面性協定同埋交換協定下。
嘅其中一項保護保障措施，係替約一方沒有責任提供。
會披露任何貿易、業務、工業、商業或專業秘密。
或貿易程序嘅資料，包括法律專業保密權所涵蓋嘅資料。
對有關。
就有關對法律專業保密權所涵蓋嘅材料嘅披露限制，對税務局係有法律約束力嘅。
喺具體嘅操作層面，現行嘅税務豁免資料披露規則已定有通知同埋複核機制。
讓當事人可向税務局局長及財政司司長提出修訂行章披露嘅資料。
如任何人士因任何行政決定而感到受屈，可向法院申請司法複核。我哋認為現行機制已平衡各方面嘅因素，例如個人私隱。
資料交換嘅有效實施，同埋國際條約嘅義務。
為咗回應法案委員會，有委員就税務局遵從保障措施。
嘅關注，我哋樂意擴展現時税務局服務承諾關注委員會嘅職權範圍。
讓有關委員會。
檢視税務局嘅定。
誒檢視税務局定期提供關於資料交換請求嘅服務，以及處理上訴嘅情情況。
具體嚟講，税務局會定期向服務承諾關注委員會報告其資料交換嘅表現，例如接獲資料交換請求嘅宗數、所要求交換資料嘅細項分類資料、處理狀況。
接獲上訴嘅個案數目，以及有關人士提出嘅投訴數目等。
然而，税務局不會向服務承諾關注委員會披露個別。
資料請求嘅詳情已符合全面性協定或者係交換協定嘅保密條文。
有關條文已實施，成為本地法律。
事實上，我哋現時已就資料交換請求設立通知同埋複核機制，讓當事人可以。
資料與實資料與事實不符，或與其本人無關為理由，要求税務局局長修訂行章披露嘅資料。
如該人仍不滿意，可向財政司司長提出複核嘅要求；如該人仍受仍感受屈，可向立可向法院提出司法複核。有關安排一直行之以有效，亦可以為亦為呢個納税人提供保障。
我哋認為有關擴展税務局服務承諾關注委員會嘅職權嘅建議，以能有助提升對税務局處理資料交換嘅監察。
亦都平衡咗各方面嘅因素，例如資料交換嘅有效實施同埋國際。
條約嘅義務。
部分持份者關注到日日後香港所接獲嘅資料交換請求會隨之增加，因而對我哋嘅公共財政資源造成影響。
參考咗其他税務管轄區嘅做法，我哋現時嘅構想係考慮向提出請求方收取就索取及獲提供所要求所要求嘅資料所產生嘅非一般成本嘅費用。
而一。
判執行本地税務法例法令所產生嘅成本，則由税務局自行承擔。
今後喺推展全面性協定或交換協定中嘅工嘅。
喺推展全面性協定或交換協定嘅工作時，我哋會一如既往由相關持份者參與其中，包括不時諮詢商界同埋專業界別，透過税務局網頁向公眾公佈即時開展嘅商討工作，喺有需。
必要時與個別團體會面，以及定期向税務聯合聯絡小組彙報。
喺未來嘅日子，我哋會繼續爭取擴展香港嘅全面性協定網絡。
與此同時，我哋會因應。
一些税務管核區嘅訴求，而與之開展交換協定嘅商討工作。
我哋亦會不時檢視已生效嘅協定，以便與協定夥伴嘅主管當局提出任何有關協定實施嘅問題。
隨住國際社會對提升税務透明度及多邊合作嘅期望與日俱增。
政府當局將因應在全面性協定。
同埋交換協定框架下所得嘅交換資料經驗。
審視香港嘅資料交換安排。
我哋會密切留意二十國集團及經合組織喺推動自動或自發嘅交換税務資料方面嘅發展。
鑑於國際標準嘅不斷演變，我哋會繼續與香港持份者保持溝通。
探討相關嘅政策同埋法律事宜，以其為香港定立一套可持續發展嘅資料交換模式。
主席，總的來説，法案委員會支持條例草案嘅建議，我懇請各位議員支持通過條例草案，讓有關嘅建議可以盡快落實。
主席，我僅此陳辭，多謝。
現在我喺提出嘅待決議題係二零一三年税務修訂條例草案予以議讀，現在付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。
我認為議題獲得在席議員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。
二零一三年税務修訂條例草案，全體委員會審議階段，本會現在成為全體委員會。現將各位提出嘅待議議題係以下條文納入二零一三年税務修訂條例草案。
第一至九條。
有冇委員要發言？
咁現在我喺提出上述代決議題，付諸表決，贊成嘅請舉手。
反對嘅請舉手。我認為議題獲得在席委員以過半數贊成，我宣佈議案獲得通過。全體委員會再回覆為立法會三讀。